so this video is just for me to practice
talking about the project that we're
proposing for the June ballot
what I want to describe is how we put
together to territorial projects one in
Agua ponds the biosphere reserve in the
northern part of Costa Rica and the
other in the talamanca region which is
one of the most biodiverse and least
negatively impacted regions of Costa
Rica that's to the south this is a set
of mountains of big mountain range that
then connects into large mangrove and
coastal estuaries system with quarries
and so these two areas one to the north
and one to the south are both primed for
being catalyzed into bio regional
territories so in both cases there are a
large number of regenerative agriculture
projects agroforestry and agro ecology
projects retreat centers and training
centers where people can learn
permaculture and other related practices
efforts to set up food forests and local
schools for helping educate children
that are aligned with biomimicry
approaches or regenerative practices
also they work at three levels where
what this grant we can help create
immediate impacts in specific projects
or land parcels so there's a for example
the opportunity to bring in the savory
Institute and train farmers who only
know traditional practices but are
interested in converting their farms to
regeneration to help a number of them do
this also we can set up a monitoring and
tracking system and help work with the
territorial councils and create
multi-stakeholder collaborations
around value exchanges and supply chains
in the regional economies so that they
become more visible better understood
and then have developments added to them
that help them function better based on
what we learn so our idea here is to
create robust circulation within
regional economies in two parts of Costa
Rica and doing this in a way that helps
us advance a national strategy of making
Costa Rica the first fully regenerative
nation on earth which we measure by
keeping it within the donut economics
model advocated by Cantrell worth and so
there's a lot that I could say about
that part but the basic idea here is
that we combine the existing strengths
of many projects on the ground with
territorial collaborations that are at
the bioregional scale where a lot of
work has already been done to build
capacity and infrastructure and so it's
ready for a mapping process and a
capacity enhancement process that's
co-created with the local people this is
in a sense what we're trying to do and
what we want to demonstrate from this is
that guided intentional change can
happen at the territorial level and that
we can measure and track improvements of
circular economy at local project up to
local / regional economy levels and that
this can be done systematically as part
of a larger national systems change
strategy what the goal that all of this
is made available to learn and be
replicated by other regions around the
world
and we want to do this with the help of
a two-year grant from the dawn
foundation and putting together that
proposal now so it's pretty exciting
what we're trying to do and just thought
that this little discussion would to
help explain a bit more of what it is
there are a lot of parts involved so
this doesn't really answer all of the
questions but I
the short video at least gives you an a
sense of how we are building the
learning and capacity building to
implement regeneration at the scale of
bioregions something that we need to
learn to do all over the planet
I hope this is helpful and certainly
helpful for me to pick it through this
way